Tavish Aggarwal

Data Scientist, IIIT - Bangalore

4 years of extensive experience in Predictive Modeling, Computer Vision, NLP, Deep Learning, AlOps, and Cloud ML Services. Additionally, I have a skill set of developing the production-ready application using the MEAN stack. Seeking for an opportunity where I can transform the company's data towards business excellence and enhance the decision-making process.

tavishaggarwal1993@gmail.com

Hyderabad, India

github.com/tavishaggarwal

7358685734

in linkedin.com/in/tavishaggarwal

WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior Software Engineer (Data Scientist) GGK Tech - An ACS Group Company

01/2020 - Present

Hyderabad

- Leading teams in the field of Data Science across the predictive modeling domain.
- Currently working on Bank Risk score prediction for the client in the aerospace industry.
- Exploring Reinforcement Learning and Deep Learning to build a knowledge base in the company.

Software Engineer (Data Scientist) **GGK Tech**

08/2017 - 01/2020

Hvderabad

- Worked as a Data Scientist in the domain of healthcare, telecom, and e-commerce.
- My major contribution was solving problems like Healthcare Claims Classification Problem, Customer Churn Prediction, and Customer Lifetime prediction.
- Worked as a full-stack developer on Angular and NodeJS.
- Played a key role in the teams and took the responsibility of end to end deliverables.

Software Engineer

MAQ Software 06/2016 - 07/2017

Hvderabad

- Worked on technologies like HTML, CSS, SQL, SharePoint workflow, java, C#, Amazon web services, and AngularJS.
- Worked in an agile model with a 100% on-time task delivery record.
- Took challenge to learn and work on cutting edge technologies.

EDUCATION

PG Diploma in Machine Learning and AI International Institute of Information Technology

06/2019 - Present

Bangalore

Bachelor of Technology in Software Engineering SRM University

Chennai

SKILLS

Computer Vision Predictive Modeling

Natural Language Processing

Deep Learning

Keras

AWS Cloud

Python Django Flask

HTML

JavaScript

NodeJS

COMPANY PROJECTS

Aerospace Industry: Bank Risk Score Prediction

- Played a major role to identify the problem statement as predicting the risk score of each and every bank account in the system.
- Worked with stakeholders to collect the captured data points and developed the tree-based model which was able to identify risky bank accounts with 83% accuracy.
- Implement SHAP for model interpretability to unravel the patterns behind model's prediction.
- Proposed and implemented Authorization Management workflow to handle false positives predicted.

Ecommerce: Login Anomaly Detection

- The client was facing economic loss because of unethical users accessing the system.
- Build the unsupervised model using the KNN algorithm from the PyOD package to find anomalous users.
- Model achieved 20% of improvement in the revenue.
- Implemented a flask solution to host the developed solution on the lambda function (as a Serverless Server).

Telecom Industry: Customer Churn Prediction

- Analyzed client's historical data and helped them to find meaningful insights from the data using visualization tools like seaborn and matplotlib.
- Developed model using the SVM algorithm for the churn prediction. Trained hyperparameters and used RBF kernel to achieve results.
- Model replaced the rule based system and achieved improvement of 27% to predict churns.

Healthcare Industry: Claims Data Analysis

- Use case was to read EDI files data and generate a dashboard for the
- Used lambda function to read the EDI files when uploaded and convert it to relational dataset.

LANGUAGES

Fnalish Full Professional Proficiency Hindi Full Professional Proficiency

2012 - 2016